

Yudhajit Adhikary

Front End Developer

Meticulous web developer with over 3 years of front end experience and passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. Implemented new responsive website approach with complete unit testing and SEO which increases performance and traffic of the website.

- yudhajitadhikary@gmail.com
- Yudhajitadhikary.github.io
- github.com/Yudhajitadhikary

- 6371272905, Kolkata, India
- in linkedin.com/in/yudhajit-adhikary-500898159
- ou yudhajitadhikary.medium.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jumeirah (Dubai Holdings) React & UI developer

05/2019 - 07/2019

05/2019 - 07/2019 Mindtree ,Bangalore
Designed responsive website with React JS library, used Redux for state
management and SCSS for styling.

Great American Insurance Company React & UI developer

07/2019 - 01/2020 Mindtree,Pun

Designed website using react component library Material Ui and React Hooks.Worked with npm packages like recharts, D3JS, Muuri. Achieved 80% code coverage in Sonar Qube using Jest and Enzyme.

Downy US P&GReact developer

01/2020 - 07/2020 Mindtree,Bangalor

Designed fully responsive website using Contentful as CMS, GraphQl as query language, NextJS as React Framework, Mobx for state management, Tailwind css.

Olay Canada P&G React developer

08/2020 - 11/2020 Mindtree,Bangalor

Worked with GSAP for animation. Worked in performance improvement.

Gillette Portugal P&G React developer

12/2020 - 03/2021 Mindtree,Bangalor

Setting up environments, creating pipelines, giving build and deployment on Azure.

Gillette Taiwan P&G React developer

04/2021 - 07/2021 Mindtree,Bangalore

Worked on third party applications PriceSpider, BazarVoice, Swiftype and Algolia.

Gillette Singapore P&G React developer

React develope

Mindtree,Bangalore

Worked with SEO,GA and GTM for Event tracking and Website Traffic Analysis.

Gillette Korea P&G React developer

12/2021 - Present Mindtree, Bangalor

Created Automation script for content migration on Contentful.

EDUCATION

College

KIIT University, Bhubaneswar

ReactJS

CSS & SCSS

NodeJS

SKILLS

Javascript ES6

Tailwind CSS

MongoDB

Redux

Windows & IOS

HTML 5 Mobx

GIT

NextJS GraphQL Express

Azure Unit Testing

Google Analytics

-0

SEO

CERTIFICATES

Developing Mobile Apps for the Android Platform (07/2017)

IOT Internet of Things -IIT Varanasi (12/2017)

Google Analytics Individual Qualification (07/2021 - Present)

SEO Certification Semrush Academy (03/2022 - Present)

ORGANIZATIONS

Mindtree (01/2019 - Present)

Senior Software Engineer

INTERESTS

Technical Blogging

Music

Photography